All the people think
if they grow their audience
that they'll automatically make
more money. But actually,
if you look carefully, you can see
that the opposite is
true. Have you noticed
that some smaller accounts online
are making a lot of money,
and actually the bigger accounts
are those that are broke?
And you can tell because
if you look at the paid endorsements
that they're doing,
yeah, they're getting a million views,
but they're having to get Squarespace to
pay
for an advert in the video just to keep
the lights on.
Whilst the smaller accounts
are running ad-free
and getting everyone to buy out
their cohorts of their courses,
their mentorships, their webinars,
whatever it is.
The biggest misconception with this
is that the smaller accounts have got a
niche,
and it's because they've honed in on a
niche that they're making so much money
and
the large accounts are broad.
But the reality is quite a bit different.
And I've actually fallen into this trap
firsthand.
And although I sit here as someone
that can hopefully help you
and educate you and
help you with your business,
I have a real big problem right now
that no one can
see from the outside. I don't know
if it's going to make me come across good
or bad
to accept this. Your audience isn't
and shouldn't be measured just in
size.
Because some of those people in those
audience are going to be followers and
some of them are going to be buyers.
For a long time,
I optimized for followers.
My main Instagram account,
my main YouTube account,
my main TikTok account.
YouTube, half a million. TikTok,
nearly two million. Facebook, 1.1 million.
Instagram, 1.4 million. Now this account,
this YouTube, just about 50K.
I've curated an audience of buyers.
But on Instagram, I
was very guilty of curating an audience of
followers.
And there is a difference. The reason
that the big accounts are often broke is
because they're big accounts.
Let me explain this in a kind of weird
way.
It is almost impossible for 99% of people
to get over a million
followers without becoming an entertainer,
without becoming someone that
tears down businesses, a contrarian.
It is almost impossible to go above a
million followers without being
anti-establishment,
but also through gaming the algorithm.
Now, gaming the algorithm
is very difficult with just education
and it's very
difficult with just problem-solving.
The character you need to become to be a
massive account is more
congruent with getting followers than it
is buyers.
We see these smaller accounts,
under 50,000 subscribers or under 50,000
Instagram followers,
they've never been tempted by that.
They've just honed in on getting an
audience of people that buy their stuff.
If you want a prime example of an audience
of followers, let's look at "Love
Island." You go on "Love Island" not for
people to buy your stuff, just purely an
audience.
You come off "Love Island," you have
millions of followers.
Yeah, they'll come to maybe a nightclub
if you're doing a PR event.
But the sponsorship deals you get
are indicative of how broke you are.
You don't really, I don't think,
get paid to go on "Love Island"
and you just cash
out the deals you can get whilst you've
got your name in the limelight.
And then one of the probably exceptions to
the rule would be someone like Alex
Hormozi,
who has gained millions of followers just
through teaching people how
to sell.
You wouldn't see an Alex Hormozi video
and, "This video is brought to you
by Squarespace." So the term we're going
to coin these people is giant
brokies.
Because if you take their sponsors away,
they're broke.
There is no underlying business.
They have a follower-based economy, not a
client-based economy.
And I'm about to admit that I was lucky
because whilst I was building a
follower-based economy, I
was bringing a red-hot
audience of clients with me.
So I sold out the Hammersmith Apollo,
sold out many
tours,
been a "Sunday Times" number one
best-selling author three times.
So I'm not shitting on what I did.
I'm just saying I wasn't aware of the
difference until later on.
There aren't many people on the internet
that have built
a follower-based economy
and a client-based economy.
I'm now currently operating two,
and this is where I'm fucked.
Because my manager, rightly so,
wants me to focus my
attention into my follower-based economy.
Because the follower-based economy
is going to be the one
that takes Noonic to the
next level.
Although I work with thousands of
businesses every year on my
mentorship,
there is not enough numbers of those for
us to survive in retail.
But the issue is I'm very much enjoying
making content for my client-based
economy,
this video.
And also I'm heavily incentivized because
I'm making
extortionate amount of money in my
client-based economy.
But I now need to start focusing my
attention more into the follower-based
economy.
That's why we have the podcast
and I'm making some more strategic hires,
which I'll
expand probably in another video.
If I could go back in time,
I would not do what I do now.
I would do what I'm about to teach you.
I want you to look at me as a perfect
example of not how to do this.
You're going to need to take your
follower-based economy, entertainment,
getting
out there, contrarian, annoying people,
and your client-based economy,
running a very good sales system using the
four S's that I'm about to teach you.
And I need you to combine those into a
follower-client, a client,
a follower-based economy.
Because I did spend years just
chasing followers
and I have spent years just chasing
clients.
Should've done both.
I can't go back in time, but you can.
So let's map this out.
So when you hear me talk about the four
S's, the first S we need to look at is
social. Now as far as the strategy,
there's some things we need to look into.
Frequency is one of the first places you
want to look. Short form, one per day.
And eventually we want to get long form,
one per week. That's gold standard.
Any questions about that,
ask me in the comments.
Now what are you going to talk about in
your content? Okay, first things first.
We must work back from a problem.
Every good product stems from a problem.
These headphones
were created because people wanted to
listen to music and didn't
want to bother people that
are around them.
This RODECaster was created because
microphones for podcasts
require power and other settings to be
taken into a computer.
So they created the RODECaster to.
We created Noonic because energy drinks
are great,
but if you could create one that
was more in line with people looking to
sit and focus and record podcasts and
edit and lock in, that would be better.
This monitor was created by Apple because
people didn't want to look down at their
laptop.
This iPad solved the problem of needing a
device on the go that was sleek
and easy to watch things on where you just
needed a screen.
This set of Hollyland Bluetooth
microphones were created to solve the
problem of
audio not being good enough in videos.
My reading glasses
were created to solve the problem
that I have.
Oh, I've been wondering where mine is.
To solve the problem of me being blind
when I'm on screens.
Everything you see in here solves a
problem.
The chalk bin was to solve the problem of
chalk going everywhere.
This fridge was to solve the problem of
drinking Noonic that was warm.
The trap bar solves... You get it, right?
Everything is a problem.
Solve problems. Bash. Okay,
next thing we need to look at,
and probably the most
important of all of them, buckets.
So when I say buckets, we
are going to need to create different
silos of things
that you're going to talk about.
So for my business mentorship,
quite loosely, I
don't really plan the videos that much.
The buckets surround doing a live screen
recording, going through people's content,
driving signups To people to apply for web
critiques.
Me doing off-the-cuff videos like this.
But if you wanted to look at someone more
famous. Let's look at MrBeast.
His buckets would be 24 hours in,
last to leave, biggest versus
smallest, most expensive versus cheapest.
They're different buckets,
so he can go along.
Last to leave could be last person to take
their hand off the Lamborghini gets to
keep it.
Last person to take their hand off the
private jet gets to keep it.
Last person.
So they then have a theme
that they go with on the buckets.
So this is where things get interesting.
What we're going to call this is A and B.
A is going to signify follower-based
economy, client-based economy.
Now,
these have to be brought into mind
when we create our buckets.
So let's create some buckets here.
These four buckets,
let's say you're a coach.
I'm just going to say personal trainer
because it's what I did for a long time.
Fat loss, muscle, food, react video.
Now, I would say here,
for follower-based economy,
the react video is probably
going to be the best one,
because reacts get better views.
You can be a contrarian,
you can be all the things you need to.
And again,
I would say follower-based economy
probably deserves better on food.
Now, I'm not going to gun her, but I will.
Lucy Lord, one of my friends,
is a fucking idiot because she does
not take the opportunity presented to her
with the food stuff sir.
She goes, "Oh yeah, good for you.
It's right for you." Listen,
my audience are
entrepreneurs and business owners
that want to use social media to make more
money.
You cook food, Lucy.
You fucking make food.
Do you know how many humans eat food?
All of them.
Like as a personal trainer in the UK,
16% of people have
got a gym membership. Cool.
But everyone fucking eats.
So when you make food stuff,
you can fucking dominate the
follower-based economy
because everyone fucking eats.
Shaun Casey made over a fucking million
dollars
selling a PDF with recipes in,
and he won't mind me saying this, it was
shit. It was fucking terrible,
but you're worth what you charge.
And that's me just spitting facts
and being a little bit jealous
that you made that
from a PDF. Then we look here,
client-based economy.
Now,
when you look at it through this lens,
you can realize here you want to be
polarizing,
you want to be in people's faces,
whatever.
Here you're going to get a big receptive
audience, kind of like free advertising of
what eats. Here, you don't need the views,
you don't need the amount of engagement,
because here's where you win them over,
and this is where you convert them.
And it's going to make more sense in a
second.
But first of all,
we need to look at a scale that
is just important for you to
understand. So here is a scale. 10,
I fucking love you.
Minus 10, I fucking hate you. Zero.
Where do you think you start
when someone's scrolling on reels
and they see you for
the first time? No, it's about here.
Now take a mental screenshot of that.
When I see your face for the first time,
it's not neutral, it's minus three.
It's I do not like you. You
are on my feed. Who the fuck are you?
Get the fuck off.
Every time someone scrolls away from one
of your reels, what
they're saying politely is, "Fuck off."
You have three seconds,
and that's being generous, to
get someone to like what you're talking
about, which is why you need to work
on your hooks. Again,
I've got Short-Form Content Mastery.
There's going to be a link in the
description. I can teach you all of this.
If any of you want a framework,
if you don't believe me, this
is a framework I've
been using with my clients at the moment.
Three words. Okay?
You're going to start a hook with three
words.
Let's use a barber, for example.
Your fades shit.
You're going to get a lot of people,
men especially, with fades going,
"What?" But
don't worry,
I'm going to teach you what you can do
instead.
Your haircut sucks.
Because you're a middle-aged man,
you're going bald, here's
some alternatives
that you could use for your haircut.
Squats don't work.
To optimize lower body hypertrophy,
this is a better thing to do.
If you can try and create a hook that's
three words long, you can stop people's
attention. Then the next 10 seconds
is to get them to like you,
because let me tell
you,
they do not like you the first time
they've seen you.
So to recap this social part very quickly,
there's your frequency.
That's what you're talking about. This
is the thing to be mindful of.
That's James Smith PT,
that's James Smith business mentorship.
You guys can mix the two,
which I'm saying if you're a small account
right now,
you can do this. It's too late for me.
You're going to put your content into
buckets.
You're going to turn up on Monday, cool,
fat loss. Next day.
And
keep in mind that people hate you, okay?
So don't wear the gimpy little vest.
Don't wear a stupid little hat.
Don't try fucking inside jokes.
Don't try and be the funny guy.
Don't say, "Hey,
guys." Because they're just going to go,
"Fuck off."
As a default, people do not like you,
and the sooner you can get out of
your fucking head,
you can start getting people to like you,
okay?
Now, that's just the first stage. Cor,
this is going to be too long for a reel,
isn't it? Social is my first one.
Next one is called squeeze.
Now,
this is where you can temperature-test
everything you're doing to make sure
you're not in a follower-based economy all
the way.
We want to aim to have 20% of all the
people on your follower list in here.
Follower-based economy up here. Now,
if they don't buy your shit, who cares?
They're not interested, who cares?
If they're following you,
enjoying the content,
it's great because these people
watching your stuff,
it's going to help grow this.
But if it's only 1% to 5%, this
is potentially that you've just
neglected your email list,
but it's also an indicator that you
are optimizing for
the wrong thing,
and you might end up having to do what no
one wants to do and put
Squarespace ads in your video.
And this video wouldn't be possible
to be here today without our sponsor,
Squarespace.
I don't even have flipping monetization
turned on for this channel.
Never done a paid ad.
Some days I've thought about it.
But if this is you right now,
you must prioritize getting to here.
And if you're trying
and it's really difficult,
it's because you've been creating
the wrong type of content.
So go back to the stage
that we spoke about before, get
that right until you're up to this
position. Now,
how do we get people to join?
Good question. There
is a free Lead Magnet Mastery course in
the description.
You click that, there's no silly buggers,
it's completely free.
It's to stop me repeating myself in
videos.
Honestly, that we
were going to charge $1,000 for it,
we gave it away for free.
And that's not because I'm just like a
nice guy or generous.
Giving it away for free got us loads of
leads. I know.
We ended up making fucking loads from it.
Absolutely loads.
You'd think it'd make me happy,
but not really.
I'm just here in love with the game.
Like George W. Bush. You think about it.
Let's not get carried away. All right.
That's enough whiteboard in for now.
But that metric alone,
you'll be able to understand so much about
your audience.
So even though we've still got the sell
component underneath, by looking at your
audience and seeing how many of them
are on your email list, you can put your
finger on the pulse of your audience to
see how many of them are in the
client-based economy because
if they're not interested in buying your
stuff, they
wouldn't have joined your email list.
Every single person that's joined your
email list is giving you a signal to say,
"Go on, keep talking. Keep convincing me.
Hmm, I want to hear more. Teach me more.
Sell to me." I was going to say daddy.
That's a bit weird.
Your email addresses correlated with your
following is the
best temperature test
that you can have to see whether your
audience
really care So once you're getting up to
that 20% of people that are on your
contact database from your following,
you know you're in a sweet spot, that you
have enough of that follower-based economy
that are interested in buying your
stuff. Client-based economy. Cool.
That means that the stuff you're doing
above it as far as content and not just
short-form, the combination of short-form,
long-form,
podcasts, posts, carousels, the lot of it,
is doing enough to
ensure that you are not pandering to just
grow an audience.
You are pandering to grow a big collective
of people that are interested in buying
your stuff. From then,
the most important thing is
that you nurture people that
have given you their contact address
through email marketing, through SMS,
through
whatever it is, emailing them,
telling them to attend webinars,
whatever it is that
you want to do to sell. But the issue
that most people face is, and myself for
quite a long time is,
I got glued to followers being the success
metric,
not the amount of followers being clients.
And then what happens
is you start getting all these feedbacks
of going viral and
growing amounts of people, "Oh my God,
you hit a million followers," that you
completely lose track of the stuff that's
important to you.
Because I got lucky, I'll admit it.
I had a red-hot audience of 10,000 people.
And keep in mind,
10,000 people with an audience of four
or five million isn't
massive.
But it was enough for me to have a few
years to figure out what I wanted
to do and to really start to hone in.
But unfortunately,
for a lot of people out there,
big YouTube accounts, big
Instagram accounts,
they're still having to promote stuff for
five grand because
they only followed the follower-based
economy, and they used the metrics, not of
how many people are joining my email list,
not how many people are using my lead
magnet, but instead how many people
are following me,
and led them down a path to
them scratching their head going,
"Why am I so skint when I have so many
followers?" It's never too late to turn
this around, but this isn't me
fear-mongering, it's just me saying this.
I did a video the other day saying I think
there's three S.
All the information in the market people
don't need anymore.
They've got AI, they've got ChatGPT,
they've got Claude, they've got Gemini.
The only thing left to sell will be
implementation. That's it.
The only thing people will pay for
is to make sure that they do the thing
they were
supposed to do. Now,
when it comes to selecting someone to
pay for implementation,
they will only pick the people
they like the most,
and the only way they can pick the people
they like the most is
going to be based on whose content they
enjoy watching the most.
It is so imperative
that you get this right,
because every five years there's a
cycle that we look back and go,
"Oh my God, I wish I knew at the time
how easy it was then compared to now."
And I think we're about to go into the
worst
one yet. If your business is in order
and everything's great,
don't work with me.
Don't join my mentorship. Good for you.
But if you're someone that's struggling to
get your views out of the thousand-view
jail, you've not started your email list,
you don't really know what to email
about,
and you're unsure how to put together a
good page that gets people to
buy without jumping on sales calls with
people and being in DMs,
it's what I do for
a living. And the reason
that my big socials get neglected so much
at the moment is
because I love talking about this stuff.
I love being in the Discord.
I love helping people with their business.
So there's a link in the description.
Make sure that when you go out there
tomorrow,
you've got an even split of trying
to get followers, trying to get clients.
If you go too far down the path of just
wanting clients, you'll never get seen.
If you go down the path of just getting
too many followers, you'll end up broke.
Hope you enjoyed that. If you
are a personal trainer
and you're not ready to buy
yet, watch this one.
Not because it's a good video,
but all the personal trainers
that watch my videos, they watch this one,
then they get their wallet out the most.
It's made like 30 grand.
So don't watch that for yourself.
Watch it for me.
All right. Bye-bye. Oh, I'm such a knob.